we've been asked
to write a program that uses a hash to
store a list of movie titles
in the year they came out we'll then use
the put s method
to print out the year of each movie to
the screen
and we've been given some example output
so let's go ahead and create our hash
we'll call it movies we surround a hash
with curly braces
and a hash consists of comma separated
key value pairs
we'll use the movie title as the key and
the year it came out
as the value
so now that we've got our hash with five
movies
we want to output only the release year
for each movie
which is the value in each of our key
value pairs
we can do this using hash element
reference
the syntax to access the value of a
given key value pair in a hash
is to use square brackets and pass in
the key
so in this case our keys are symbols
let's access the value of our first key
value pair
so we'll pass in the symbol representing
the movie jaws
and when we run our file we'll expect
that the value
1975 is what will be output
and that's what we see
returning to our text editor
we want to output each of the years
and now we expect to see each value
printed when we run our program
and we do
you